Guide to the University of Pittsburgh at Greensburg, Artifacts, 1907-present UPG.RG.69
ULS Greensburg
University of Pittsburgh at Greensburg, Artifacts
1907-present
ULS Greensburg
University of Pittsburgh at Greensburg
UPG.RG.69
43 items
Artifacts from the University of Pittsburgh at Greensburg Campus.
Access Restrictions
No restrictions.
Custodial History
Transferred from the UPG Administration to the UPG Archives.
Scope and Content Notes
[N.B.: Items stored in Archive Utility Cabinet faz 3/10/15]
* [13 buttons in H2PG Archives Artifacts exhibit case as of inventory 9/19/2017] faz
* [Paperweight in H2PG Archives Artifacts exhibit case as of inventory 9/19/2017] faz
* [Stuffed Animal and Towel in H2PG Archives Artifacts Exhibit case as of inventory 9/19/2017] faz
Universities and colleges -- Pennsylvania -- Greensburg -- Records and correspondence; Universities and colleges -– Pennsylvania -– Greensburg -– Administration; University of Pittsburgh at Greensburg
- Artifacts, 1907-present; I.
  - Banner, December 3-30, 2010; 8cm x 272cm [3.5' x 9'] (Cabinet 1)
    Scope and Content Notes
    Inscription: University of Pittsburgh--International Service--Rotary International-- Students of the University of Pittsburgh at Greensburg (Study Abroad IFTA--India) Works hand in hand with Rotary Club of Durgapur Central in community projects DIST 324. [Banner taken by UPG students on their IFTA [Integrated Field Trip] to India, Dec. 3-30, 2010. [See: UPG News Release 02/04/2011.] faz 9/12/2019
  - Bas-Relief sculpture of Leonardo da Vinci, 18" x 20" (Cabinet 1)
    Inscription: "University of Pittsburgh at Greensburg Da Vinci Scholar". In Frame.
  - Buttons, 1982-2007 (Cabinet 1)
    Pitt Panther Football buttons. [ca. 1982-2007?]*
  - Certificate, 1989; 8 1/2" x 11" (Cabinet 1)
    Framed. Inscription: "You have proven there is one force as powerful as Mother Nature: Human Nature." The American Red Cross recognizes with gratitude the help given by University of Pittsburgh at Greensburg to the victims of the 1989 disasters. American Red Cross.
  - Certificate, December 14, 2004; 13" x 10" (Cabinet 1)
    Plaque. Inscription: "The Society of Success and Leadership. This to Certify that Parris Carter has successfully completed The Society of Success and Leadership training program and committed to further leadership development. In light of this accomplishment, membership has been conferred in the University of Pittsburgh-Greensburg Chapter of Sigma Alpha Lamda, The Society of Success and Leadership.
  - Certificate, December 11, 2015 (Cabinet 1)
    StormReady [Certificate of Recognition [in a Certificate Folder] awarded by the United States Department of Commerce National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration National Weather Service to University of Pittsburgh at Greensburg for successful implimentation of the StormReady Program.]
  - Certificate, 2017; 11" x 8" (Cabinet 1)
    Unframed. Inscription: "2017 Readers' Choice Silver Award presented to the University of Pittsburgh at Greensburg. Category: College/University Westmoreland by the readers of Trib Total Media."
  - Christmas Ornament, August 18, 2017 (Cabinet 1)
    Aluminum Christmas Ornament. Inscribed: "Hillman 50 Anniversary". [Designed and crafted by artisans and craftsmen of Wendell August. Given to the staff members of the University of Pittsburgh Library System (ULS) at their Aug. 18, 2017 Annual [Staff] In-Service Day to commemorate the 50th Anniversary of the Hillman Library (opened Jan. 8, 1968, dedicated Sept. 6, 1968) on the University of Pittsburgh Oakland Campus.]
  - Decal, 2003 (Cabinet 1)
    [40th Anniversary University of Pittsburgh at Greensburg 1963-2003]
  - Face Cover, 2020 (Cabinet 1)
    Pitt Face Cover issued to all faculty, staff, and students during COVID-19 pandemic.
  - Hard Hat (Cabinet 1)
    University of Pittsburgh "Hard Hat" [construction helmet]
  - Lapel Pin (Cabinet 1)
    University of Pittsburgh, Greensburg
  - Lynch Family Gift, 2002 (Cabinet 1)
    Original covering of a medieval-looking armchair given in May 2002 to UPG by Elizabeth R. Schmidt. Received in UPG Archives, Nov. 2002.
    See Also
    [prints of the gift in original condition may be found in UPG.RG.60 Visual Images--Prints--Lynch Family Gift items; for original correspondence in re the gift, See UPG.RG.02.4 Ser.: Correspondence.]
  - Lynch Family Gift, February 1, 2011; 12" x 14" (Cabinet 1)
    Framed Hand Embroidery. George Washington is My Name. [Embroidered by Mary Lynch Quinn or by another Lynch Family member. per JC Biskup, 2/1/11.]
  - Matchbooks, 1970-1980 (Cabinet 1)
    Scope and Contents
    Matchbooks (6) Pitt Greensburg Campus Student Activities Bldg.
  - Paperweight, May 17, 1977; 2" X 3" (Cabinet 1)
    Marble paperweight. Science Building Dedication Greensburg Campus.
  - Paperweight, 1988; 3" X 4" (Cabinet 1)
    Glass paperweight. University of Pittsburgh at Greensburg Lynch Hall 25th Aniversary [sic] 1963-1988.*
  - Pin, 2005 (Cabinet 1)
    UPG PLCB Designated Driver
  - Plaque, 1907; 4"x 7" (Cabinet 1)
    Inscription: Charles McKenna Lynch US Naval Academy 1907. Presented to the University of Pittsburgh by the US Naval Academy Alumni Association 1970. [Received in UPG Archives from the UPG Office of the President 11/21/02]
  - Plaque, 2002; 7"x 10" (Cabinet 1)
    Inscription: Strongland Chamber of Commerce Established January 1, 1985. University of Pittsburgh at Greensburg. Member 2002. Presented by the Board of Directors.
  - Plaque, August 24, 2001; 8"x 11" (Cabinet 1)
    Inscription: Heinz Field [the Steelers' and Panthers' new stadium. [Pittsburgh Trib].
  - Plaque, 2004; 5"x 7" (Cabinet 1)
    Inscription: 2004 Quest for the Best. Best College or University. University of Pittsburgh at Greensburg Gold Winner in the Tribune Review 2004 Readership Awards.
  - Plaque, 2004; 7"x 5" (Cabinet 1)
    Inscription: American Heart Association. 2004 Westmoreland Heart Walk. 3rd Place Top Team Award University of Pittsburgh at Greensburg.
  - Plaque, 2001; 10" x 8" (Cabinet 1)
    Inscription: American Heart Association. University of Pittsburgh at Greensburg Top Fundraising Team. 2001 American Heart Walk.
  - Plaque, 2001; 6" x 8" (Cabinet 1)
    Inscription: Patron Donor. Boy Scouts of America. University of Pittsburgh at Greensburg. Westmoreland Fayette Council 2001.
  - Plaque, 2003; 5" x 7" (Cabinet 1)
    Inscription: 2003 Quest for the Best. Best College/University. University of Pittsburgh at Greensburg Winner in the Tribune Review 2003 Readership Awards.
  - Plaque, 2008; 12" x 13" (Cabinet 1)
    Inscription: The City of Greensburg thanks the University of Pittsburgh at Greensburg for supporting Summer Sounds--Greensburg's Concerts in the Park.
  - Plaque, 8" x 10" (Cabinet 1)
    Inscription: Central Blood Bank recognizes University of Pittsburgh at Greensburg Campus for their outstanding support and commitment to the community blood program. Central Blood Bank.
  - Plaque, 1993-1994; 11 1/2" x 14" (Cabinet 1)
    In Grateful Appreciation Collegiate Sponsor of the Year University of Pittsburgh at Greensburg. American Red Cross.
  - Plaque, August 15, 2014; 8" x 10" (Cabinet 1)
    Inscription: "Presented to Frank Zabrosky Friends of the Library Excellence Award 2014. In recognition of Friends of the Library who have displayed exceptional support to the University Library System." Nominated for the award by the UPG Millstein Library Staff. Presented at the 7th Annual "In-Service Day", Friday, August 15, 2014, Hillman Library.
  - Plaque, 2014; 8" x 10" (Cabinet 1)
    Inscription: "Congratulations. Trib Total Media. Quest for the best 2014. University of Pittsburgh at Greensburg has been selected as one of the best businesses in the area!"
  - Plate, 1989; 10" diameter (Cabinet 1)
    Inscriptions: "University of Pittsburgh Staff Recognition Award Presented for Service Beyond 10 years to Dorothy A. Weber".
  - Quilt, 2001; 40" x 60" (Cabinet 1)
    "UPG Beginnings" completed in 2001. Quilters: Dolly Biskup, Beth Cassell, Pat Duck, Jennifer Fetter, Karen Gavula, Mary Louise Hill, Joyce Rossman, Clara Vana, Nancy Young. Covers the tenure of the first President of UPG, Dr. Albert B. Smith, 1962-1980.
  - Quilt, 2003; 56" x 71" (Cabinet 1)
    "Building UPG" completed in 2003. Covers the tenure of the second president of UPG, Dr. George F. Chambers, 1980-1997. Quliters: Dolly Biskup, Joyce Bucchi, Sandy Buehner, Beth (Mrs. Frank) Cassell, Marion Chambers, Pat Duck, Jennifer Fetter, Mary Louise Hill, Holli Ramaley (student), Joyce (Mrs. Carl) Rossman.
  - Quilt, 2004; 46" x 94" (Cabinet 1)
    "40th Anniversary", completed in 2004. "The Quilters, a volunteer group of faculty, staff and students created this quilt in honor of UPG's 40th Anniversary. Quilt consists of autographed signature patches of the various constituencies of the campus community."
  - Shadow Box, 8" x 10" (Cabinet 1)
    Emblematic representation, a Green Sock, of the SOC (Sustainable Office and Classroom) Building, now known as Cassell Hall [Frank A. Cassell Hall].
  - Stuffed Animal, 1987 (Cabinet 1)
    Pitt Panther. Pitt Bicentennial 1787-1987.
  - Stuffed Animal, 1987 (Cabinet 1)
    Pitt Panther. Pitt Bicentennial 1787-1987. [duplicate]*
  - Stuffed Animal, 2010 (Cabinet 1)
    Pitt-Greensburg "Bruiser" Bobcat.*
  - Towel, 11" x 15" (Cabinet 1)
    Inscription: "Pitt Greensburg Bobcats".*
  - Trophy, 1985-1986 (Cabinet 1)
    [2nd Place] College Debates on Energy, "Penna. Electric Assoc. & Westinghouse Electric Corp."
  - Trophy, 1990-1991 (Cabinet 1)
    [Third Place] College Debates on Energy, 10th Anniversary, "Penna. Electric Assoc. with Westinghouse Electric Corp. and General Electric Co."
  - Weaving, 2000 (Cabinet 1)
    by Felipe Hernandez Vicente presented to Dr. Frank A. Cassell on the occasion of the UPG Homecoming 2000.
  - Window Cling (Cabinet 1)
    [University of Pittsburgh at Greensburg]